Guide to the Zena Bailey Sutherland Papers 1953-2003
University of Chicago Library
Sutherland, Zena Bailey. Papers
1953-2003
16 linear feet (32 boxes)
Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center University of Chicago Library 1100 East 57th Street Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.
Zena Bailey Sutherland (1915-2002) (AB 1937, AM 1958 University of Chicago) was associated with the University of Chicago Graduate Library School throughout her career as faculty and as editor and reviewer for the Bulletin of the Center for Children's Books from 1958 to 1985. Over the course of her career, she reviewed more than 30,000 children's books, for the Bulletin and as children's book editor for the Saturday Review and the Chicago Tribune. She authored six editions of the classic text Children and Books The Sutherland Papers consist of materials from work in the Graduate Library School, papers regarding her service on the Newbery, Caldecott, and other children's literature award committees, speeches and writings, biographical materials, and correspondence related to her professional work at the University and as editor and author for children's literature.
Information on Use
Access
Series VIII contains student material and is restricted until 2080. Some items in Series VII are currently restricted due to fragile condition on the need for special equipment.
Biographical Note
Zena Sutherland was born in Winthrop, Massachusetts in 1915 and raised in Chicago. She graduated from the University of Chicago in 1937 and in 1958 earned a master's degree in library science from the University, intending to pursue a career as a medical librarian. Her experience as a mother of three children inspired her to take several courses in children's literature.
Sutherland was among the world's most influential and prolific scholars of young people's literature. She was associated with the University of Chicago Graduate Library School throughout her career, and served as a faculty member there from 1972 to 1986. She wrote 19 books and reviewed more than 30,000 children's books during more than 40 years as a critic of children's literature. From 1958 until her retirement in 1985, she served as reviewer and editor of the Bulletin of the Center for Children's Books, a comprehensive guide to all the latest literature published for children. She wrote monthly columns as children's books reviewer for the Saturday Review from 1966 to 1972 and also served as children's book editor for the Chicago Tribune. In 1972, she succeeded May Hill Arbuthnot as author of Children and Books, a classic textbook in the field of library science and children's literature for which she produced the fourth through ninth editions.
She served on numerous book award juries including the National Book Award, the Hans Christian Andersen Award, the Jane Addams Book Award, the Laura Ingalls Wilder Award, the Caldecott Award, and the Scott O'Dell Award for Historical Fiction of which she was the permanent chair. As a member of the American Library Association, she was a jurist and member of the Newberry and Caldecott award committees. Sutherland also served on the United States Board of Books for Young People, acting as a children's literary ambassador in South Africa, China, and other countries.
In 1983, two former students used the royalties from a Festschrift in her honor to establish the Zena Sutherland Lecture Series, and the Lab Schools at the University of Chicago also recently established the Zena Sutherland Prize in Children's Literature, which is awarded by children of the School. In 1998 she was awarded the Norman MacLean Faculty Award, and named professor emeritus Zena Sutherland.
Sutherland married Roland Bailey in 1937. They had three children before divorcing in 1961. In 1964, she was remarried to Alec Sutherland, director of broadcasting and head of the Center for Continuing Education at the University of Chicago. Zena B. Sutherland died in Chicago on June 12, 2002.
Scope Note
The Zena Sutherland Papers contain correspondence, manuscripts, teaching materials, research notes, clippings, photographs and audio and video recordings. The Papers are divided into eight series.
Series I: Biographical Materials primarily contains articles and interviews with Sutherland from the 1970s through the 1990s. The series also includes materials related to Celebrating Children's Books, a festschrift published in her honor in 1981, and a small amount of personal correspondence.
Series II: Graduate Library School, primarily contains lecture notes and other materials related to courses taught by Sutherland. A small amount of correspondence and other items related to the GLS are also included.
Series III: General Files, contains files related to organizations with which Sutherland worked and boards on which she served, including the American Library Association, the Children's Reading Round Table, the International Board on Books for Young People and the Scott O'Dell Award Committee. Also in Series III are files on the Zena Sutherland Lecture Series.
Series IV: Correspondence documents Sutherland's career as an educator, author, reviewer and associate of many in the fields of both librarianship and children's book publishing. Among her main correspondents were author Lloyd Alexander, educator Susan Cooper, and editor Ursula Nordstrom. A large number of notable children's book authors are among her correspondents.
Series V: Writings, Speeches and Publications, documents Sutherlands work as author, editor and reviewer. It includes correspondence, manuscripts, clippings, reprints and promotional material for books, articles and speeches. Sutherland's correspondence with publishers is generally included with the files for the publications discussed, but more generally exchanges are in Subseries 4 of Series V.
Series VI: contains clippings and photocopies of articles related to the subjects of Sutherland's teaching and research, organized by subject. Also included are several files of "author profiles," comprising mostly publishers' promotional material and articles about children's literature authors.
Series VII: includes a small number of photographs and recordings of radio or other public appearance by Sutherland.
Series VIII: contains student related material to which access is restricted.
Related Resources
Browse finding aids by topic.
Subject Headings
Sutherland, Zena; University of Chicago -- Center for Children's Books; University of Chicago. Graduate Library School; Book reviewing; Children -- United States -- Books and reading; Children's literature, American -- History and criticism; Children's literature -- History and criticism; Children -- Books and reading; Library education; Library Science; Children's Literature; Children's literature -- Book reviews; Young adult literature
INVENTORY
- Series I: Biographical Materials
  - Biographical articles and interviews, 1978-1998 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Biographical article, Library Trends, interview, draft, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Biographical dictionaries and press releases, 1975-1996 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Biographical clippings, 1969-1999 (Box 1, Folder 4-7)
  - Awards and degrees, 1957-1998 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Celebrating Children's Books: Essays on Children's Literature in Honor of Zena Sutherland, correspondence, 1979-1981 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Memorial Services, 2002-2003 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Personal correspondence and documents, 1965-1998 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Series II: Graduate Library School
  - Graduate Library School, 1966-1993 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Graduate Library School, GLS 321, Children's Literature, reading lists and lecture notes, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Graduate Library School, GLS 326, Reading of Adolescents, reading lists, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Graduate Library School, lecture notes, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Graduate Library School, student writings, 1976-1991 (Box 2, Folder 9-11)
- Series III: General Files
  - American Library Association, Children's Services Division and Association for Library Service to Children, 1960-1994 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - American Library Association, Association for Library Service to Children, 1995-2000, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - American Library Association, Association for Library Service to Children, Pre-conference on Children's Picture Books, planning materials, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - American Library Association, Association for Library Service to Children, Newbery and Caldecott Medals, 1976-1996 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Annenberg Public Policy Center, Conference on Children and Television, 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 5-7)
  - Annenberg Public Policy Center, Conference on Children and Television, 1996-1997 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Arbuthnot Honor Lecture, 1969-1996 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Arbuthnot Honor Lecture, 1972, Mary Orvig, publicity and correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Center for Children's Books, 1958-1988 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Center for Children's Books, correspondence, 1960-1990 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Carl Sandberg Award (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - People to People Children's Literature Travel Program (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Children's Book Council\ (Box 4, Folder 8-10)
  - Children's Books, advance proofs, Hughes, Ted, Season Songs, Ill. Leonard Baskin Sendak, Maurice, In the Night Kitchen (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Children's books, advance proofs, Helprin, Mark, Swan Lake, ill. Chris Van Allsburg, 1989 (illustrations only) Macaulay, David, Black and White Sendak, Maurice, We Are All in the Dumps with Jack and Guy Russo, Marisabina, Alex is My Friend Bernstein, Joanne E. and Bryna J. Fireside, Special Parents, Special Children (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Children's Reading Round Table, 1958-1996 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Children's Reading Round Table, Bulletin, 1967-1983 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Children's Reading Round Table, Bulletin, 1987-1996 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - International Board on Books for Young People, 1966-1992 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - International Board on Books for Young People, Hans Christian Andersen Award, 1975-1998 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - International Board on Books for Young People, US Board on Books for Young People, 1991-2000 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Jane Addams Book Award, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 7A)
  - Notes and fragments, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Notes and fragments, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - U.S. BBY, Board of Directors (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - International BBY, Board of Directors (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Children's Book Council (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Notes on England, Claire and Fasick, Adele M., ChildView, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Scott O'Dell Award, correspondence and notes, 1981-1996 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Scott O'Dell Award, publicity and press reports, 1981-1998 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Stationery with miscellaneous letterheads (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Zena Sutherland Award, 1996-2001; and Letters to ZS from Lab School 4th graders, 1999. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Zena Sutherland Lecture, correspondence and notes, 1981-1995 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Zena Sutherland Lecture, Maurice Sendak, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Zena Sutherland Lecture, Lloyd Alexander, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Zena Sutherland Lecture, Katherine Patterson, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Zena Sutherland Lecture, Virginia Hamilton, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Zena Sutherland Lecture, Robert Cormier, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Zena Sutherland Lecture, Paula Fox, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Zena Sutherland Lecture, David Macaulay, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Zena Sutherland Lecture, Jean Fritz, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Zena Sutherland Lecture, Trina Hyman, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Zena Sutherland Lecture, Betsy Byars, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Zena Sutherland Lecture, Walter Dean Myers, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Zena Sutherland Lecture, Patricia MacLachlan, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Zena Sutherland Lecture, Susan Cooper, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Zena Sutherland Lecture, Rosemary Wells, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Zena Sutherland Lecture, Avi, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Zena Sutherland Lecture, Laurence Yep, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Zena Sutherland Lecture, Ashley Bryan, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Zena Sutherland Lecture, Russell Freedman, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Zena Sutherland Lecture, Lois Lowry, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - National Book Awards (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Quadrangle Club Revels and other campus theater, 1953-1961. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - 37 Players Theater Group. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Writings by others, Brooks, Jerome, "A Wing Growing Back," manuscript and correspondence, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Writings by others, Stanek, Lou Willett, Whole Language - Literature, Learning and Literacy, manuscript, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Writings by others, miscellaneous papers, 1985-1996, undated (Box 8, Folder 5-6)
  - Writings by others, Holt, Henry, "Borrowed Finery," 2000 (Box 8a, Folder 1)
  - Writings by others, Rollins, Charlene, “Sissy,” 1972 (Box 8a, Folder 2-3)
  - Writings by others, Slepian, Jan, “Travels with Clara,” undated (Box 8a, Folder 4)
- Series IV: Correspondence
  - A, 1958-1998, Aardema, Verna, 1973 Aberg, Ylva, 1978 Adams, Shaneena Alderson, Brian, 1974. Alexander, Alison Harris, 1998 Alexander, Greg, 1995. Alexander, Lloyd, 1968-1999 Allen, Elizabeth, 1969-1971, 1990-1992 Allen, Patricia, 1967. Anderson, Adrienne Adams, 1971 Anderson, (John) Lonzo Anderson, Gordon T.R., 1979 Andresen, Tish C., 1977 Andrews, Mary Evans, 1994 De Angeli, Marguerite, 1969 Antonowich, Linda, 1994 The Art Institute of Chicago, 1991-1993- Asch, Timothy, 1958 Asheim, Lester, 1985-1992 Asimov, Isaac, 1958-1970 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - B, 1966-1999, Baker, Augusta, 1968. Ballou, Mary Ellen, 1971 Bamberger, Richard, 1966, 1971 Barron, Thomas, 1998 Barstow, Barbara, Cuyahoga County Public Library,1997 Bartow, Roy E., 1970. Bass, Doris, 1972. Batchelder, Joy, 1981 Bartoli, Jennifer, 1975 Beckman, Beverly, 1967 Beckman, Delores, 1985 Beitler, Roslyn, 1995 Bell, Arthur, 1968. Benasutti, Marion, 1969 Beneduce, Anne, 1967 Bennett, William W. 1967 Berger, Maureen, 1977 Berger, Paula, 1986 Berkelhamer, Jay, 1988 Bernstein, Joanne E., 1977 Berrent, Howard, 1982 Beull, Carol, 1983 Bhabha, Homi K. Biegel, Paul, 1971 Billingsley, Franny. Bishansky, Susan, 1977 Blanco, Elena M., 1996 Blatt, Gloria, 1976 Bloomfield, Brian David, 1998 Blos, Joan W., Blum, Norma Mann, 1967 Blume, Judy, 1996 Bob Roberts Service Committee, 1979-1981 Bond, Beverly, 1967 Bonsall, Grosby Booklist Bowen, Brenda, 1986 Bothwell, Jean, 1965 Boyd, Alda Lee, 1969 Bradley, Kevin, 1966, 1996 Bragdon, Elspeth Braidwood, Gretel, 1993, 1998 Branley, Franklyn M., 1981 Brent, David, 1978 Brett, Jan, 1996 Briley, Dorothy, 1969-1973, 1981, 1993 Broderick, Dorothy M., 1973-1976 Brodie, Deborah, 1991 Brome, Charles W., 1968 Brooks, Jerry Brooks, Vicki Brooke, Sally Brown, Richard H., 1989 Bryan, Ashley, 1999 Buehler, Katherine Maynard Phillips, 1979 Bulla, Clyde Robert, 1968 Burch, Robert Bob, 1971 Burchardt, 1966 Burell, Carol M., 1995 Burwash, Carol, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - C, 1965-1999, Callaghan, Linda Ward 1991 Cameron, Ann 1991 Cameron, Eleanor, 1973 Canapi, Mary Ann 1987 Cantigny, 1984 Carnovsky, Ruth, 1985 Carroll, Frances Laverne 1978 Cart, Michael 1983 Center for Scholars and Writers, The New York Public Library, 2000 Chambers, Bradford, 1969 Chapman, Ginny, 1968. Childs, Mary C, Children's Book Council, 1965 Chapin, 1996 Chapman, H. Virginia 1967 Chicchi, Luciana 1986 The Children's Book Center, 1977 Children's Literature Assembly, 2001 Childs, Mary C. 1964 Chlebek, Diane, 1984 Chubb, Dell Ciardi, John, 1969 Clark, Ann Nolan Clark, Portia M. 1981 Cobb, Vicki 1988 Colby, Jean Poindexter 1967 Cole, William, 1967 Coleman, Lonnie, 1982 Coles, Robert, 1972 Collier, Carmen 1971 Cooper, Ilene 1995 Cooper, Liz 1985 Cooper, Susan 1972-1999 Cormier, Robert 1987 Correro, Gloria, 1988 Council on Interracial Books for Children, 1969-1971 Cousins, Norman 1966 Crampton, Patricia Criscoe, Betty 1998 Croft, Carolyn 1976 Crosby, Alexander 1971 Crossley, Winnifred Moffett 1965 Cullinan, Bernice Cullinane, Irenemarie 1977, 1984 Curlow, Betty Cushman, Jerry 1966 Cuyler, Margery S. 1980 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - D, 1959-2000, Dahlberg, Thelma, 1985 Daly, Joe Ann, 1967 Darehshori, Nader, 1991 Dawson, Julia, 1979 De Angela, Rachael 1981 Deadrick, Lee Anna, 1968. Dell, W.R. 1965 Dickson, Kathy 1998 Dillon, Leo and Diane 1976 Donohue, Joanne 1989 Donovan, John, Children's Book Council, 1969-1993 Dorris, Michael, Correspondence and Biographical Material Dorsey, Charles, 1968 Doubleday Books for Young Readers Downie, Sarah 1985 Dragonwagon, Crescent 1990 Dubo, Elyse 1995 Dubose, Alice H. 1992 Duff, A. 1960 Duff, John B. 1990 Duncan, Sue, Sue Duncan Children's Center Dunlap, David 1999 Durrell, Ann 1966, 1986 Duvoisin, Roger 1971 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - E, 1959-2000, Eaton, Nancy 2000 Eisenberg, Michael 1986 Ellington, Whyte, 1990 Emerson, William R. Emery, Anne 1971 Epstein, Eileen W. 1997 Esmonde, Margaret P. 1977 Eulass, Elizabeth 1959 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - F 1966-1996, Fader, Shirley Sloan 1969 Fallers, Margaret 1993 Federici, Yolanda D. 1973 Feelings, Tom 1982 Fenger, Sadako. Fenty, Allan A. 1974 Felt, Mary 1991 Fern, Lois, 1985 Field, Carolyn W. 1975, 1994 Finer, Judy 1993 Fisher, Sonja, Women's Board, University of Chicago, 1993 Fisher, Leonard Everett 1993 Fitzmaurice, James, Scott, Foresman and Company, 1987 Flaherty, Rose 1979 Flammer, W.H. Foss, JoAnne, 1989 Fosser, Joanna Fox, Paula 1970-1982, 1995 Frank, Eugene 1978 Fraser, James H. 1976 Freeman, Evelyn B. 1999 Freeman, Ira M. 1968 Friermood, Elisabeth Hamilton 1966 Frith, Margaret, 1977 Fritz, Jean 1967-1979, 1990 Fry, Bernard M. 1978 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - G, 1960-1999, Gabarino, Nan, 1994 Gagliardo, Ruth, 1973, 1974 Galvin, Thomas J. 1977 Gans, Roma 1981 Garber, Benjamin 1994 Garst, Doris Shannon 1971 Gauch, Patricia Lee 1988, 1994 Gauthier, Mary E. 1986 Gebel, Doris Gerhardt, Lillian, 1978 Giannotti, Judy, 1967 Gifford, Carolyn de Swarte 1994 Gilbert, Edwyna 1983 Gilpin, Rebecca 1996 Gipson, Morrell 1968 Goldberg, Beverly 1997 Goodman, Kenneth S. 1982 Gordon, Elizabeth 1988 Gossett, Philip 1993, 1999 Graham, Sarah 1968 Gray, Hanna Holborn 1985-1987 Greenaway, Ann, 1967-1970 Gregory, Valiska 1995 Groff, Patrick 1972 Grosscup, Clyde 1967 Gruenberg, Sidonie M. 1960 Grusin, Claire, 1969 G'sell, Sue Mitchell 1996 Guettel, Mary Rodgers 1982 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - H, 1961-2000, Haas, Dorothy 1975-1994 Hahn, James 1973 Hahn, Lynn 1973 Hamilton, Virginia Harmon, Mary K. 1961 Harshaw, Ruth, 1966 Haskins, Jim 1977 Hallworth, Grace 1985 Harrison, Pat, U of C Vice President Hatton, Mary A., 1973 Haviland, Virginia 1960 Hautzi, Ester 1969 Hautzig, Debbie 1980 Hayes, Alice Hearne, Betsy 1980-1989, 1999 Heide, Florence Parry 1975 Heins, Ethel L. 1995 Hellen, Wendy Henkes, Kevin, 1998 Henry, Marguerite 1978 Hentoff, Nat 1964-1972 Herman, Cheryl 1999 Hiatt, Doris, 1966 Higgins, Jazan 1989, 1995 Hill, Margaret Hinton, S.E. 1968, 1992-1995 Hirschman, Susan Hoban, Russ Holdsworth, Mary, 1967 Holman, Karen 1969 Holsaert, Eunice, 1968,1969 Horning, Kathleen T. 2000 Hopkins, Lee Bennett 1977 Hotchkiss, Mrs. Eugene 1972 Howard, Will, Texas Bibliographical Society, 1977 Hoyle, Karen Humara, Ruth, 1981 Humphries, Shirley, 1967 Hunt, Paul 1997 Hunter, Edith, 1971 Hunt, Paul, 1997 Hyde Park Neighbors Club, 1993 Hyman, Trina (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - I-J, 1966-1998, Iordanova, Dina 1997 International Research Society for Children's Literature, 1984-1987 Iron, Mary Itumara, Ruth S., Friends of the Library of Hawaii, 1981 Jackson, Jackie 1971-1982 Jackson, Richard W. 1967-2000 Jacob, Helen 1977 Jacques, Faith, 1991 Jagusele, Sybille, 1991 Jarchow, Larry, 1970 Jasin, Marianne, 1970 Jenkins, Lyll Becerra de, 1989 Jennison, Christopher 1993 Jolis, Gillian, 1969 Jones, Helen L. 1966-1967 Jones-Diggs, Barbara Johnson, Crockett 1967 Johnson, Neville 1975 Johnston, James R., Joliet Public Library, 1989 Jorgenson, Timothy 1975, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - K, 1967-1999, Katz, Susan R. 1990 Kayden, Mimi 1967-1976 Kearney, Meg, 1999 Keating, Charlotte M. 1971 Keller, John G. 1971 Kelley, Jane T., 1974 Diana King, 1999 King, Marian 1967 Kearl Family 1991 Keating, Charlotte, 1971 Kellman, Amy Kerr, M. E., SEE Meaker, Marijane Konigsburg, Elaine L. 1968-1978 Korshak, Jack 1966 Krane, 1993 Krasnopolsky, Fara 1988-1992 Kronovet, Jennifer, 1998 Kraus, Robert, 1968 Kruse, G. 1993 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - L, 1965-1997, Laber, Jeri 1979 Lakeshore Unitarian Society, 1998 Landau, Elliot, 1969 Lanes, Selma, 1975 Lauber, Patricia 1965 Latimer, Jim 1991 Laing, Frederick 1967 La Rabida Children's Hospital and Research Center, 1995-1997 Leander, Ellen 1987 Leman, Nancy 1971 Leventhal, Bennett L. 1982 Levi-Setti, N. 1981 Lewicki, Lynn M. 1969 Lichtenberg, Margaret Klee, 1974 Lilly, Barbara, 1970 Linehan, Katherine, 1991 Lipincott Company, 1961 Von der Lippe, Angela 1989 Literature Connection, 1990-1992 Livingston, Myra, 1975 Livingston, Richard R. 1972-1986 Lo, Dubby Lobel, Anita, 1972-1973, 1993 Lobel, Arnold, 1972-1973 Locke, Ms., 1983 Long, Joanna, 1975-2001 Lorraine, Walter 1977 Lorenz, Denis 1968 Lovett, Kathleen M. 1977 Lurie, Allison 1991 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - M, 1965-1999, Maas, John, Macaulay, David A. 1984, 1996 Kathy MacKenzie, 1990 MacMillan Publishing, London, 1974 Macomber, Rosemary 1970 Magorian, Michelle, 1982 Mahany, Barbara 1994 Majonica, 1978 Manchel, Frank 1973-1979 Marcus, Leonard, 1994-1997 Markiet, Antonia 1992-1998 Martin, Pam 1967-1978 Martin, Ruth Croft, 1987 Mason, John 1998 Masumoto, Lynn 1981 Mathewson, Richard D. 1967 Mathias, Beverley 1981 May, Charles Paul 1966 May, Jill, 1977 McClintock, Lillian 1961-1965 McGrath, Lloyd 1965 McCutchan, Ron 1989 McDonough, Irma, 1968 McElderry, Margaret 1967 McCrackin, Mark 1978 McGee, Dorothy Horton 1968 McGeehan, 1996 McGoldrick, Jane 1988 McGovern, Michael, 1993 McHargue, Georgess, 1968 Meaker, Marijane (M. E. Kerr),1972 Means, Florence Gannell 1968-1971 Medlock, Stephanie 1992 Melton, Diana, 1995 Meltzer, Milton 1971 Mendoza, George 1968 MENSA, 1997 Meyer, Howard N. 1966 Meyerson, Kimberly Michelmore, Mrs. C., 19798 Miers, Earl Schenck 1967 Miller, Brandon 1998-1999 Miller, Alice, 1968 Miller, Stuart Minow, Newton N. 1995-1998 Mizhemore, Jean, 1981 Monjo, Ferdinand (Ferd) 1967-1977 Morris, William, 1969-1974 Moser, Barry Mosesson, Gloria R., 1976 Moulton, Priscilla, 1975 Muehl, Lois 1967 Mulvey, Minn, 1969 Museum of Science and Industry, 1991 Mwale, Willey Jelemiya Mphonde, 1999 Myers, Barbara, 1994 Myers, Diana 1996 Myers, Elisabeth P. 1966 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - N, 1967-2002, National Geographic Society, Publications Division, 1988 Neff, Priscilla Holton Niedlow, Irina, 1996 Neigoff, Anne 1976 Neule, Emily C. 1973 Neumeyer, Peter 1986 Neuthaler, Paul, 1968 Newquist, Colleen 1995 Nicholson, George, 1968-1976 Nicholson, Wendy Webber 1967, 1970 Norris, Catherine, Wisconsin Library Association 1973 Noyes, Judy, 1975 Nye, Naomi, 2002 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Nordstrom, Ursula, 1960-1980 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - O, 1960-1998, O'Bryan, Muriel 1976 O'Connell, Margaret, 1974 O'Connor, Kathleen 1981 O'Dell, Elizabeth, 1990-1995 O'Dell, Scott 1986 Ogilvie, Mary 1999 Ohlen, M. 1972 O'Leary, Amy, 1968 O'Leary, Colleen, 1997 O'Malley, Judith, 1992 Opie, Iona 1988-1991 Orden, Susan 1990 Orgel, David (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Orvig, Mary, 1975-1992 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - P-Q, 1960-2001, Patte, Genevieve, 1982 Patti, Catherine 1998 Peck, Richard "Dick" 1974-1992 Peltola, Bette J. 1978-1983 Penguin USA, 1989 Peterson, Elizabeth M. 1976 Pevsner, Stella 1973-1979 Pfuztzenreuter, Kitty 1987 Phelan, Carolyn, 2001 Philipson, Morris 1967 Place, Marian J. 1967 Plotnick, Art 1981 Pohlman, Lillian 1972 Porter, Roy E. 1960, 1970 Portteus, Elnora M. 1974 Portugal, Anita Presberry, Rosa, 1980 Privitera, Joseph, 1967 Quint, Paula, 1973, 1992 Quirk, Anne E., 1989 (Box 10, Folder 9)